RG 089:001, State Highway Department
Connecticut State Library
- Series 21. Surveyor field books, 1956-1962; 1989-004
  - Simsbury, Bridge over Farmington River, undated; 2 volumes, No. 128-59, unnumbered, 3 (Box 3)
  - Simsbury, Route 10, undated; No. 1 (Box 3)
  - Southington, Misc. Route 20, undated; No. 131-73 (Box 3)
  - Stafford, Middle River Bridge and approaches on Route 32, undated; No. 134-67 (Box 3)
  - Stafford, Crow Hill Road, undated; 2 volumes, No. 134-69 (Box 3)
    One volume not titled
  - Tolland, undated; No. 142-61, A (Box 3)
    Volume not titled
  - Wilbur Cross Hwy widen, Connecticut Route 20 to Massachusetts State line, undated; No. 145-52, D (Box 3)
    Area covered is Union, Conn.
  - Vernon, A section of Wilbur Cross Highway, Section #4 construction and survey, undated; No. 146-41, C (Box 3)
  - West Hartford, Bishops Corner, undated; No. 155-58, A (Box 4)
  - Wethersfield, Route 5-15, undated; 8 volumes, No. 159-86, 1-A, 1-B, 2-A, 2-B, 2-C, 3, 4, Master index (Box 4)
  - Wethersfield, undated; No. 159-, Act 19 (Box 4)
  - Wethersfield, Nott St., undated (Box 4)
  - Wethersfield - Meriden, Berlin Turnpike misc. info, undated (Box 4)
  - Wolcott Garage proposed site, undated; No. 166 (Box 4)
- Series 26. Personnel Administrator, 1942-1969
  - 1995-033
    - Staff meetings, 1958 September - 1969 April; 1 binder (Box 1)
      Agendas, memos, minutes and organizational charts produced for bimonthly meetings held to improve communications between directors and heads of major units. Loose items found in binder include a list of Connecticut Hightway Department Standing Committees, June 10, 1969 and a policy memo regarding Intoxicants - Intoxication, April 7, 1969.
      Arranged in reverse chronological order.
    - Policy and procedures manual, 1945-1954; 1 binder (Box 1)
      Memos and letters regarding department and statewide policy includes partial chronological index.
      Arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Connecticut State Employees Association meetings, 1957-1963; 1 binder (Box 1)
      Correspondence, minutes, memos, agendas and other documentation regarding monthly meetings between the Commissioner and CSEA. Loose items found in binder include correspondence, agendas, handwritten notes, etc.
      Arranged chronologically.
      This is volume 3. There is no indication of the location of volumes 1 and 2.
    - General letters 1-76, 1942-1962; 1 binder (Box 1)
      Correspondence regarding administrative policy clarifications.
    - Commissioner's letters, 1941-1967; 1 binder (Box 1)
      Policy directives primarily concerning personnel issues but also dealing with daily operations. Reveals impact of outside events such as World War II on operations.
    - Business administration memoranda, 1952-1957; 3 binders (Box 1)
      Routine memos regarding policies and procedures concerning budgets, telephones, vehicle maintenance, central mail service, safety equipment, etc.
  - 1995-058
    - State Employee Council No. 16 meeting agendas and minutes, 1955-1964; 2 binders (Box 1)
      Binder labeled "#2" contains 1955 - 1959 September; Binder labeled "#3" contains 1959 October 27 - 1964 June 26.
- Series 27. Engineers' Files, 1917-1984
  - Warren M. Creamer files, 1933-1984
    Warren Milton Creamer was born in Williamsport, Pennsylvania on July 18, 1894. He graduated from Trunity College in Hartford in 1917 and began working for the Connecticut State Highway Department in 1922. He served as project engineer in charge of design and layout of the Merritt Parkway from Milford to Greenwich. He later served as the department's Director of Engineering and Construction and from 1958-1966, the year of his retirement, as Director of Staff Services. He was a president of the Connecticut Society of Civil Engineers and sat on the Highway Research Board in Washington, D.C. He died in Farmington on July 7, 1979.
    - 1995-057
      Consists primarily of research and writings on tunnel construction both foreign and domestic.
      - Awards - General Motors - Better Highways, undated (Box 1)
      - Connecticut Public Expenditure Council, Comparison of PUblic & Private Pay Scales, 1968 (Box 1)
      - Highway Department organization chart, circa 1968 (Box 1)
      - Policy manuals - updates, 1969 (Box 1)
      - Professional papers, unpublished, 1961 (Box 1)
      - Publications (Box 1)
        - Articles, draft & final, 1962, undated (Box 1)
        - Foreign translations, 1960-1961, undated (Box 1)
        - Papers, professional, draft & final, 1963, 1962 (Box 1)
      - Trinity College, book donations, 1984 (Box 1)
      - Retirement, press release, 1966 (Box 1)
      - Reports, 1958-1975; 1 binder + 9 items (Box 1)
    - 1998-040
      - Field books, 1933-1939; 19 books (Box 1)
        Contains staking data, traverse lines, and excess data sections of the Merritt Parkway.
        Books are numbered as follows: M-1, M-1-S, M-2, M-2-S, M-3, M-4, M-6, M-8, M-9, M-10, M-12, M-13, M-14, M-15, M-16, M-17, M-18, M-19, M-20.
        Index in front of each book.
      - General notes, 1937-1866
        Daily diaries of activities as employee of the State Highway Department.
        - 1937 May 16 - 1953 February 2, 23 books (Box 2)
        - 1953 February 2 - 1966 June 27 (Box 3)
      - Mileage books, 1946-1956, 1961-1966; 5 books (Box 3)
  - Harry Mardoian files, 1917-1960; 1999-143
    Harry Mardoian was a bridge designer.
    - West Rock Tunnel, 1940-1948, undated (Box 1)
      - Blueprints, 1941, 1946, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Computation sheets, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Drawings, 1944, 1948, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous, 1947, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Proposal, 1941 March 11 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Special provisions, 1940-1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Design analysis on void jobs, 1938-1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 8-10)
      Includes the following: Pumpkin Ground Road Bridge over Merritt Parkway; Thames River approach over Groton, Conn.; Bridge over connection with Route 5A, North Meadows Highway, Hartford; Woodward Ave. Bridge over U.S. Route 1; Bolton Notch interchange; Briggs St. over U.S. Route 1, New London; Bridge over Nonnewaug River on Route 47, Woodbury; Bridge over Quinebaug River on Route 101, Pomfret and Killingly; Junction box on U.S. Route 1, Groton; Relocation of Route 72 over Berlin Turnpike; Greenwich Ave. Bridge over Pawtuxet River, Warwick, R.I.; Chestnut Ridge Rd. Bridge over Derby Ave.; Route 6A over Powperaug River; Ridge Road Bridge over Hartford Bypass; Mill Plain Bridge, Route 6 over R.R., Danbury; Route 6 bridge over Quinebaug River, Killingly; U.S. Route 1 over Quambaug Cove, Stonington; unidentified.
    - State Highway Department publications, 1943-1955 (Box 1)
      - Cuts and fills, 1943-1950 (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
        Published monthly by and for the Connecticut State Highway Department
        First issue present is Vol. 2, No. 3, September 1943
        The following issues are not present: Vol. 4, No. 9, September 1945; Vol. 6, No. 10, October 1947; Vol. 9, No. 12, December 1950
      - Standard specifications for roads, bridges and incidental construction, 1955 January; 1 volume (Box 2)
        Book cover and verso of front end leaf inscribed, "Harry Mardoian"
        A copy is available at
      - Specifications for highway and bridge design by contracting engineers, 1954 May; 1 volume (Box 2)
      - Geometric highway design standards: report of Committee on Geometric Design Standards, Connecticut Highway Department, 1951 March; 1 volume (Box 2)
      - Geometric highway design standards: report of Committee on Geometric Design Standards, Connecticut Highway Department, 1954 August; 1 volume (Box 2)
    - Other publications, 1917-1949
      - Engineers' manual / by Ralph G. Hudson, S. B., 1917; 1 volume (Box 2)
        First edition
        Verso of front end leaf inscribed: "H.H. Mardoian, M.I.T. 1918"
      - Steel construction / Lee H. Miller, Chief Engineer, American Institute of Steel Construction Inc., 1928 December; 1 volume (Box 2)
        Title page inscribed: "H.H. Mardoian, 2-2/29"
      - Commercial tunnel liners, 1933 (Box 2)
        The Commercial Shearing and Stamping Company, Youngstown, Ohio
      - Commercial tunnel supports, undated (Box 2)
      - Public roads: A journal of highway research, Vol. 19, No. 7, 1938 September (Box 2)
      - Engineering news-record, 1944 November 16 (Box 2)
      - Alpha composite construction engineering handbook, 1949 (Box 2)
        Second edition
        Porete Manufacturing Company, North Arlington, N.J.
    - Photographs, 1936, undated (Box 3)
      - J.N. Cross, in charge of bridge design, George L. Dunkelberger, architect, Connecticut State Highway bridge department, 1936 September 16; 1 photograph, b&w, 5 x 7 in. (Box 3)
      - Merritt Parkway bridges, undated; 30 photographs, b&w, 8 x 10 in.; 1 photograph, b&w, 4.5 x 6.25 in. (Box 3)
        Includes: Glenville Water Company Road bridge, Greenwich; Round Hill Road bridge, Greenwich; Taconic Road bridge, Greenwich; Stanwich Road bridge, Greenwich; Rocky Craig Road bridge (now Guinea Road bridge), Stamford; Riverbank Road bridge, Stamford; Long Ridge Road bridge, Stamford; Rippowam River bridge, Stamford; High Ridge Road bridge, Stamford; Newfield Avenue bridge, Stamford; New Haven Railroad bridge, New Canaan; Ponus Ridge Road bridge, New Canaan; Old Stamford Road bridge, New Canaan; Lapham Avenue bridge, New Canaan; South Avenue bridge, New Canaan; White Oak Shade Road, New Canaan, 3 photographs; Bas-relief panel of a Puritan, Comstock Hill Avenue bridge, Norwalk; New Canaan Avenue bridge, Norwalk; Silvermine Avenue bridge, Norwalk; Perry Avenue bridge, Norwalk; State seal, Perry Avenue bridge, Norwalk; Main Avenue bridge, Norwalk; Decorative panel on abutment, North Avenue bridge, Westport; Two workers at base of abutment, Merwins Lane bridge, Fairfield, 2 photographs; Center pier and decorative iron railing, Merwins Lane bridge, Fairfield; Decorative iron railing, Merwins Lane bridge, Fairfield; Decorative grapevine on pilaster, Huntington Avenue bridge, Trumbull; Unidentified bridge
- Series 28. Blueprints, 1922-1960
  - T000837
    - Town of Westport. Plan and profile of a section of the Shore Road from Norwalk to Fairfield, April1922; 1 bundle (29 sheets)
  - 1980-040, 20 sheets
    These blueprints were discovered in the map collection in 1980 and transferred to the Archives.
    - Construction details and fittings for wire rope railing, 1935 June; 1 sheet
    - Metal beam type rail (Type R-B) & (Type MD-B), 1960 September; 1 sheet
    - Construction details and fittings for wire rope railing, 1945 March; 1 sheet
    - Type "D" "E" & "L" endwalls reinforced concrete pipe; Underdrains & outlets perforated pipe, 1942 June; 1 sheet
    - Endwalls slope paved inlets and outlets, 1942; 1 sheet
    - Fences, barways, barricades, tree well & root protection service bridges slope paving, 1940 January; 1 sheet
    - Cross sections of roads in Lebanon, Conn., 1946; 14 sheets
      There were originally 39 sheets in this set, 14 of which are present.
      - Cross sections, Goshen Road, 1946; 3 sheets
        Sheets are numbered 15, 16, and 17.
      - Cross sections, Village Hill Road, 1946; 3 sheets
        Sheets are numbered 18, 19, and 20.
      - Cross sections, Church Road, 1946; 4 sheets
        Sheets are numbered 32, 33, 34, and 35.
      - Cross sections, Colchester Road, 1946; 4 sheets
        Sheets are numbered 36, 37, 38, and 39.
- Series 29. Bureau of Fiscal Services, 1968
  - Revision "C" (No. 3) of the Manual of the Bureau of Fiscal Services, 1968 Mary 10; 1 item (Box 1)
- Series 30. Bureau of Planning & Design, 1957-1993
  - 2013-032
    - Old Route Change Notices, 1957-1963; 2 binders (Box 1)
    - Route Change Notices, 1968-1993; 1 binder (Box 1)